Hi everybody, I'm John Kiriakou, and
welcome back to the briefing room.
>> [snorts]
>> People often ask me what is the most
dangerous tool
or tools that the CIA has in its
possession.
And sometimes I tell people on podcasts
about these devices that seem to come
straight out of a James Bond movie. And
then the comment section goes, "Oh,
you're making this up. There's no way
that you're telling the truth." Well,
the truth is that much of it has already
been made public.
It's called Vault 7.
Information about it was given to
WikiLeaks, and it was allegedly leaked
by a man by a man by the name of Joshua
Schulte.
Uh before I get into the tech, I want to
tell you about Joshua Schulte.
Josh Schulte was a CIA software engineer
who was convicted on nine Espionage Act
related counts
for allegedly giving WikiLeaks an
enormous collection of classified CIA
documents that became known as Vault 7
or the Vault 7 revelations.
Schulte denied being the source, and
prosecutors built a case based on
circumstantial evidence. They said that
Schulte had the technical ability to
access the material, but that he was
angry with his bosses bosses and
co-workers, and that he was
sophisticated enough, get this, to cover
his tracks.
Let me explain.
They said,
"We have no evidence that he did this,
but the reason we have no evidence is
that he is so smart
that he covered up the evidence." At
first, it was a hung jury. They just
couldn't decide if he was guilty or not
guilty. He was tried a second time.
He made a terrible mistake
of representing himself,
and he was found guilty on all charges.
Vault 7 was an extraordinary collection
of documents detailing some of the CIA's
most sophisticated hacking and
surveillance capabilities. WikiLeaks
began to publish the files in March of
2017.
And the CIA absolutely lost its mind.
The Wall Street Journal prepared a clip
that does a very good job of explaining
what Vault 7 was. Let's go to that clip.
>> WikiLeaks released thousands of
documents and files that it says expose
hacking tools used by the Central
Intelligence Agency.
The leaks purportedly show that the CIA
is capable of hacking smartphones,
computer operating systems, automobiles,
messenger applications, and even
internet-connected televisions. The
series of files, dubbed Vault 7,
consists of 8,761
documents and files allegedly from the
CIA's Center for Cyber Intelligence.
Though many of the tools detailed in the
documents are the kind of things you'd
expect from an intelligence agency,
they provide an unprecedented blueprint
for how the CIA could hack individuals
they're spying on.
Here's how they could work. Say CIA
operatives are investigating a suspect
in France we'll call John. According to
the leaks, CIA hackers operate out of
the US consulate in Frankfurt, Germany
using it as a base to cover Europe, the
Middle East, [music] and Africa.
From the confines of the consulate, the
CIA can track John's activities around
France.
The CIA purportedly has a few techniques
it can use to hack into versions of
Apple's iOS, the mobile operating system
used in iPhones.
The WikiLeaks documents detail malware
allegedly used as a hacking tool that
appears to remain on an iPhone even
after it has been rebooted, a technique
known as persistence.
To gain access to phones and other
devices, the CIA would exploit zero-day
bugs, previously unknown flaws in the
operating system's code, that they would
collect and store.
If the CIA hacks John's phone, it can
and the encryption of messenger apps
like WhatsApp, Signal, Telegram, and
Confide that John uses and collect voice
audio and messages before the
applications encrypt John's texts.
To track his movements, the agency can
activate the camera and microphone on
John's phone without him knowing and
retrieve his geolocation. Even if his
cell phone's powered off, the documents
describe how the CIA can hack other
internet-connected devices to monitor
John's activity.
Working with British intelligence, the
CIA developed an attack that can place
Samsung smart TVs in a fake off mode.
So, while the TV appears turned off, in
reality, it's functioning as a bug and
recording his conversations in the
living room. The CIA also apparently has
the capability to target John's wireless
internet router to connect to his
infected computer or access files.
American CIA hackers can also allegedly
leave false breadcrumbs to mask the
operation's fingerprints and make it
appear that it was carried out by
another country.
>> Yeah.
Wow.
Sean Roche, who was the CIA's deputy
director for digital innovation,
reportedly described this leak as a
digital Pearl Harbor.
Federal prosecutors in this case called
it one of the most damaging acts of
espionage in American history.
And according to later reporting, CIA
officials were so furious
and so embarrassed by Vault 7 that the
agency under Mike Pompeo discussed
extraordinary options for dealing with
Julian Assange, the founder of
WikiLeaks, including plans to kidnap him
or if that were to be unsuccessful, to
kill him
in broad daylight
in the center of London.
Vault 7 showed that the CIA had
developed tools capable capable of
exploiting vulnerabilities in some of
the technology that millions of ordinary
people use every day. I'm sitting 15 ft
from a Samsung smart TV.
Now, I don't discuss classified
information in my living room, but
a lot of people do. Or not even
classified information so much as
sensitive information. Well, the CIA, if
it wants it, it can get it.
One of the most famous revelations
involved these smart TVs. According to
the documents, the CIA and its partners
developed a tool that could make a
television appear to be turned off as
you saw in the video while using its
microphone to record conversations
in the room.
Schulte's legal troubles went well
beyond Vault 7. Federal investigators
also discovered child sexual abuse
material while searching his devices,
leading then to additional charges and
additional convictions.
Those crimes are horrifying. And nothing
about the public importance of Vault 7
diminishes them.
But neither do those crimes erase what
Vault 7 revealed. Now,
Josh Schulte was sentenced to 40 years
in prison. He'll likely die in prison.
And not just prison. He didn't go to
what some people used to call Club Fed
or a low-security prison. He's in a
Supermax.
When he entered prison, he was first
sent to MDC
Brooklyn, the Metropolitan Detention
Center in Brooklyn. It is known as one
of the harshest and most difficult
prisons
anywhere in America.
Because of the severity of this crime,
because of the import of the crimes for
which he was convicted, he's not moving
down to a medium-security prison or a
low-security prison.
He's going to spend probably the rest of
his life
in a maximum.
Now, there are other things that we
learned from the Vault 7 revelations.
One of the things that's important that
you heard in that clip
uh was the issue of breadcrumbs. What a
breadcrumb is
is a false
hint
that's left on a digital trail. A
breadcrumb on a trail.
In this case, what a breadcrumb is is
just one line of code
or maybe even one word of code
that's left for someone to find in a
hack.
But the code is written in Russian
or in Farsi
or in Chinese.
So, it doesn't look like the Americans
or the Brits did this hack.
It looks like the Russians, the
Iranians, or the Chinese did the hack.
Vault 7 is also known as the crown
jewels of the CIA. Now, the CIA had no
official
official response to Josh Shulties' uh
revelations other than this comment that
this was a digital Pearl Harbor. It was
if if you're a CIA leader. It was a
digital Pearl Harbor. I for one am glad
to know what the CIA can do against me
as a private citizen. But at the same
time, it exposes these highly classified
secrets to hostile foreign powers.
One of the things that wasn't in that
clip was another revelation coming out
of Vault 7 that the CIA can remotely
take over by hacking
the computer in your car.
Now, why would they do that? Why would
they hack into the computer that runs
your car? I can tell you why.
To take over the car to drive you off a
bridge
or into an abutment or into a tree
so that it looks like it was just a
terrible accident when they find your
dead mangled body.
Or it looks like a suicide.
It doesn't look like you were
assassinated by remote control from a
long distance
by the CIA. Have you ever wondered what
it feels like to shoot with the same
precision tech used by US special
forces?
Well, good news. After years of research
and development, MCG Tactical just
dropped something incredible.
The Stinger Combat Sight. This is not
your average red dot. Using holographic
technology once reserved for elite
military and law enforcement, the
Stinger delivers crystal clear
precision. So accurate you could hit a
dime at 300 yards without even trying.
This is the exact same level of
technology used by the pros, but here's
the twist.
Most sights like this go for 600 bucks
or more and people happily pay it.
But right now, through an exclusive deal
with MCG Tactical, you can get this
mil-spec sight for under $200.
And it gets better.
For my listeners, you're getting 67%
off and they're covering the shipping
costs.
Seriously, this is something you are not
going to want to miss. Just scan the QR
code or go to mcgtac.com/johnsting
to get yours today. The only catch,
supply is tight and these things are
flying off the shelves. So, if you want
a sight built for the best, now is your
shot. Grab yours before they have to
shut down orders. That is
mcgtac.com/johnsting.
Another part of Joshua Schulte's case
was the length of this sentence.
Many observers thought that Schulte was
going to get 20 years for this. I I this
this was a serious crime if indeed he
was guilty of it, but
but 20 years is a long time. Two decades
in prison? I mean, the traitor Jonathan
Pollard got 30, and his information went
directly to the KGB. Josh Schulte got
40. Why? Because this wasn't really just
about Josh Schulte.
This was about a chilling effect.
This was a message to all CIA employees
saying,
"You're thinking of going public?
Look what we did to Joshua Schulte.
Do you want to die in an 8x10 foot cell
40 years from now?
Because you will."
It's not an accident that there haven't
been similar leaks of technical data
from the CIA. Everybody watched the
Joshua Schulte trial.
The Justice Department,
it was revealed just recently,
has just subpoenaed a journalist named
Matthew Cole.
Matthew Cole is a freelance reporter.
He had been doing some work for the New
York Times,
and he had reported on a failed Navy
SEAL Team Six mission
that had taken place inside North Korea.
The Justice Department wants to know who
talked to him.
Who told him about this top secret
mission?
Most people are talking about this in
terms of attacks on press freedom.
I'm talking about it because Matthew
Cole put me in prison.
So, here are the facts of the case. The
Department of Justice has investigators
who are seeking Matthew Cole's testimony
about 2 years worth of information
uh about his contacts,
and about conversations that he had with
those contacts, as the DOJ investigators
try to identify Cole's sources for the
article about this very sensitive, as I
said, top secret operation in North
Korea.
Matthew Cole's lawyer said in a
statement, "Mr. Cole has dedicated his
professional life to bringing official
misconduct to light and informing the
public about the workings of its
government." Unquote. "His client," he
added, "will not be intimidated from
continuing that important work. He will
defend press freedom and the First
Amendment from this administration's
brazen attacks on journalists and he
will honor his commitment to his
sources." Unquote.
That's bull
I'll get to that in a minute.
As a refresher
on his North Korea reporting that got
him in trouble, Matthew Cole reported on
this top secret mission in which US US
special forces, specifically SEAL Team
Six, the most sensitive of all the SEAL
Teams,
was to plant an electronic listening
device inside Kim Jong-un's office
amid high-level nuclear talks with
President Trump.
It went horribly wrong.
The mission was so secretive that SEAL
Team Six had to complete the mission in
complete radio blackout.
But when they had just gotten ashore,
flashlights from a North Korean fishing
boat
pointed in their direction.
They thought they were caught by North
Korean military.
They immediately shot up a boat full of
fishermen.
They swam over to the ship.
They punctured their lungs,
the lungs of the fishermen,
so that they could drown their bodies
and sink them to the bottom of the of
the ocean to hopefully avoid getting
caught.
This was an immense embarrassment for
the US military.
And it seemed like I like it had been
leaked by sources with an axe to grind
against SEAL Team 6 over frustration
that they were attempting incredibly
stupid operations and only getting
publicity for the successful ones.
Somebody ratted them out and they ratted
them out
to Matthew Cole.
Let me tell you about Matthew Cole.
I used to work with Matthew Cole at ABC
News. We both worked for Brian Ross in
the investigative team.
I was the counterterrorism
commentator along with uh Dick Clarke,
the former
counterterrorism czar at the White
House.
Matthew was a junior
investigative reporter gathering content
for Brian Ross to use in his reports.
Uh
we weren't
close. We were cordial to one another on
those rare occasions when we would see
each other.
In 2008
in July
Matthew Cole
called me.
And he said that he was writing a book
on something called the Abu Omar
rendition. Abu Omar was uh a Muslim
cleric in Milan, Italy.
Kind of a firebrand.
And the CIA had gone to the Italians and
said, "We really don't like this guy Abu
Omar. We want you to help us kidnap
him."
And the Italians said, "What are you out
of your minds? This guy hasn't committed
any crime. Just cuz you don't like his
sermons doesn't mean that he should be
kidnapped."
So the CIA just kidnapped him anyway
on their own.
And they when they kidnapped him, they
sent him to Egypt. He's Egyptian. They
sent him to Egypt specifically to be
tortured.
And the Egyptians tortured him for
something like 9 months.
And then they came back to the CIA and
they said, "Look, this guy doesn't know
anything. He's just a preacher. He
doesn't like the United States,
but he's not like Al-Qaeda. He's not a
terrorist. He's just
a preacher." And they let him go. And he
returned to Italy and he told the story
of his kidnapping and rendition to
Italy. The Italians were furious. And so
they they issued arrest warrants for all
of the CIA people involved in the
operation. Everybody was under cover,
but every single one of them made a
mistake with their cover. You're under
cover, some made up name, and then you
use the hotel phone to call your wife in
your true name.
Or you're under cover and you go
souvenir shopping and you use your
actual credit card in your real name.
They were able to identify every one of
these guys. Almost all of them escaped.
A couple of them had like serious
multiple felony arrest warrants issued
against them.
This was
an operation that caused immense
embarrassment to the CIA.
So, Cole was writing this book about it.
And he emails me
and he says, "I have this list of 12
names. Do you know any of these guys who
I could interview for my Abu Omar book?"
And I looked at the names. I said, "I
don't know who any of these people are.
I can't help you."
He sent me a second email with a list of
another 12 names. And he said, "Can you
introduce me to any of these people?"
And I said, "Look,
kidnapping wasn't my thing at the CIA.
You obviously know this issue far better
than I do. The only thing I know about
Abu Omar is what I've read in the
Washington Post. I don't know any of
these people."
And then he sent me a third email.
And he said, "What about the guy that
you mentioned
on
page 160-something
of your first book? I think his name is
John." And I said,
"Oh, you're talking about John Doe.
I don't know whatever happened to him.
probably retired and living in Virginia
somewhere.
I forgot about it. Three and a half
years later, I was arrested by the FBI
and charged with five felonies including
three counts of espionage.
Espionage sometimes carries with it the
death penalty.
I was looking at 45 years in prison.
Why?
Because Matthew Cole was never writing a
book about Abu Omar.
In fact, the cover of the book which he
had sent me as a PDF,
he just made it up on the internet.
Matthew Cole was secretly working for
the Guantanamo defense attorneys.
And so he passed John Doe's name to the
Guantanamo defense attorneys and they
wrote a classified motion asking the
judge to allow them to depose John Doe.
The judge recognized this
as
a leak.
And so the judge turned the name over to
the FBI. The FBI went to the Guantanamo
defense attorneys and said, "Where'd you
get this name?"
And they said, "We got it from Human
Rights Watch."
And then they went to Human Rights Watch
and said, "Where'd you get this name?"
And Human Rights Watch said, "We got it
from our investigator John so-and-so. I
don't remember his name anymore."
And then they went to John so-and-so.
"Where'd you get this name?" "I got it
from Matthew Cole."
And then they went to Matthew Cole.
"Where'd you get this name?" He says,
"John Kiriakou gave it to me. John
Kiriakou was my source."
And then they arrested me
and changed the course of the rest of my
life. I went to prison for 23 months
because Matthew Cole ratted me out to
the FBI
and then to the grand jury.
Now Matthew Cole is a champion
of press freedom.
He refuses to out his sources for this
SEAL Team Six uh
book that he wrote or article or
whatever it was.
But it wasn't just me that Matthew Cole
did this to.
After he left ABC News, he was he was
asked to leave ABC News because of my
case. He couldn't be trusted as a
journalist. He had lied.
And he ended up at The Intercept.
Well,
Reality Winner was a translator
at NSA.
And she believed that
the Russian government was
helping the Trump 2016
campaign committee
to win the 2016 election.
And so she sent a one-page classified
analysis
about Russia and Russian involvement in
the 2016 election to The Intercept.
Matthew Cole received it. Now, on The
Intercept's webpage, they always say,
"Hey, if you have classified
information, here's our encryption key.
Send it to us.
You know, we'll we'll break the story."
So, Reality Winner sent this one-page
analysis to The Intercept. It went to
Matthew Cole.
And what did Matthew Cole do with it?
He scanned it.
He emailed it to NSA
and said, "Is this a real NSA document?"
But this is a guy who's supposed to be a
seasoned national security investigative
journalist. He's so stupid
that he didn't know that in the
intelligence community
to guard against leaks,
whenever you print a document,
your employee ID number is embedded in
the dot of an I or in a period at the
end of the sentence.
So, all NSA had to do was blow up
the the document, look at the dot of the
I, and it says, you know, Reality Winner
and has her number. She was arrested 4
hours
after Matthew Cole published the story.
She did 5 years and 3 months in prison
because of Matthew Cole.
And guess what?
The story's not over.
There was also a courageous FBI agent by
the name of Terry Albury. I'm proud to
say that Reality and Terry are friends
of mine now.
Terry Albury
had filed a case against the FBI for
racial discrimination. The FBI is
notoriously racist.
He was a special agent in the FBI's
Minneapolis office.
Passed over for promotion despite being
even more competitive than than many of
the white FBI officers who had been
promoted ahead of him.
And so
a study was done, an internal study,
about racism at the FBI. He took a
picture with his phone of the screen
where he had the the document up on the
screen.
And then he sent an encrypted version of
it
to The Intercept. It was received by
Matthew Cole.
And Matthew Cole outed him to the FBI.
And Terry Albury was arrested and
charged with espionage and convicted
and sent to prison.
I actually tweeted at The Intercept
when this happened. And I said, "Hey
Intercept, serious question.
You guys aren't really that stupid, are
you? You aren't really that bad at
journalism, are you?
You're really just a front for the FBI,
right?
Matthew Cole left The Intercept and has
been a freelance journalist ever since.
I don't know how the man feeds himself.
But now, all of a sudden,
he's a champion
for freedom of the press.
I'm going to follow this case very
closely, and I'll update you as soon as
there's a development. Let me tell you
what's happening while the legacy media
sleeps. This could be the biggest story
of the decade, and you won't hear a word
about it from the traditional talking
heads. I spent years inside the US
government. If that experience taught me
one thing, it's this: Pay attention to
what governments do, not what they say.
So, watch what China is doing. They shut
down paper gold trading at four of their
largest banks. Same move, same day. They
keep physical gold wide open, build a
new settlement system through Hong Kong,
and expanded their vault capacity
tenfold.
The official explanation is that they're
protecting retail traders from
volatility. I've read a lot of official
explanations in my life. This one
doesn't hold up. China's trade surplus,
about 1.2 trillion dollars a year. Their
gold imports, about 940
tons a year.
Divide one by the other, and you get
what gold would have to be worth if
China ever pays its bills in gold
instead of dollars.
$38,000
an ounce. That's just simple math.
And what is our government doing while
China prepares? It's printing
trillions in interest on debt that
they'll never repay. Every dollar they
print out of thin air makes the dollars
you saved your whole life worth less.
Nobody voted for that tax, but everybody
pays it, especially the savers and
retirees who did everything right.
I've seen how this works from the
inside. The people in charge will not
send you a warning letter. That's why I
want to tell you about my friends at
American Alternative Assets. They help
everyday Americans protect their
retirement with physical gold and
silver. And they're one of the most
trusted precious metals companies in the
country. A+ rated with the Better
Business Bureau. Over 50,000 Americans
served and a 100% US-based team.
They put together a free report called
The Day Money Changes Forever. Inside
you'll discover why gold could be headed
to $38,000
an ounce and the easiest way to protect
your life savings before the crowd
catches on.
A real US-based specialist walks you
through it. No pressure. Get your free
copy at johnlovesgold.com
or call 888-GOLD-053.
Don't wait for the official explanation.
By then it's already happened.
There was a situation in Idaho earlier
this week where a man walked into a
fast-food restaurant and just began
opening fire on people. What I'm going
to say is
probably going to be a little
controversial. And if you want to hate
on me in the comments, go ahead and hate
on me.
But
our Constitution gives us
the right to bear arms.
I've always considered myself to be
a progressive, a leftist.
But I feel very, very strongly about my
right to carry a gun.
I lost my right to carry a gun because I
have a felony conviction. I'm appealing
that to the Department of Justice right
now.
But the reason why this massacre wasn't
far, far worse is because an honest
citizen was carrying a gun.
I mean, wouldn't it be wonderful if
there were no guns for anybody?
You know, and we could be like, I don't
know, Sweden or whatever. But we're not
like Sweden. That's not the reality. The
reality is we have lots and lots and
lots of guns in this country. And what
protects us from the criminals, cuz the
cops can't always do it,
is honest citizens
with their own weapons.
I think that this is going to be part of
of the broader debate.
Because this happens
more frequently than most Americans
realize. Now, when Donald Trump was
inaugurated the second time, he ordered
the Justice Department to
begin reinstating the gun rights of
felons
who have no violence in their cases, no
drugs in their cases, and no connection
to organized crime. That's me.
In April of 2025, the Justice Department
issued a statement saying the president
had given this order, that they were
going to build a website, and you could
go to the website and click on the link
and fill out the form, and ATF would do
an investigation, and you'd get your gun
rights back.
They have not updated that since the day
that they posted that message.
And so, I decided
because in the words of a formerly
uh
well, in the words of an attorney that I
once went against, I'm a litigious
prick.
And so, I'm going to file a suit against
the Department of Justice
to get my gun rights back.
Now, a presidential pardon would give me
my gun rights back.
And so, I've applied for a presidential
pardon. I have both broad and deep
support for a presidential pardon, but I
can't count on a pardon. The CIA doesn't
want me to be pardoned institutionally.
I can't count on it.
And so, I'm going to go for my gun
rights back.
And that's another thing that I'm going
to keep you updated on.
I want to do something a little bit fun,
too.
We're going to be ranking politicians
on how good of a case officer I think
they would be.
How good of a CIA operations officer
they would be using what's called the
S-tier rating system. I am told by my
younger producer that S means you would
be one of the best case officers in the
whole CIA. And it goes all the way down
to F, which means you would probably be
horrendous, you would probably sell
state secrets to a foreign government
for money, or you're sleeping with your
source.
So, uh, so let's take a look, actually.
Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez.
Uh,
yeah. You know what? I'm going to be a
nice guy, and I'm going to give her a C
because
there's probably a certain kind of
person
who would be attracted into her as a
case officer and would probably
volunteer information to her.
The next one is Hakeem Jeffries.
I'm going to give Hakeem Jeffries a D
because Hakeem Jeffries is a know-it-all
narcissist
who cares only about his organization,
right?
His party.
He doesn't really care about the the
greater good.
I just don't trust the guy.
Next, we have Ro Khanna. I like Ro
Khanna very much.
I'm going to give Ro Khanna an A.
And I'll tell you why. I think Ro Khanna
is one of these very few selfless
people.
Ro Khanna cares about the greater good.
I think that he would
I think that he has cut the kind of
personality where people want to be
around him.
And and I think that that would make him
a successful case officer.
Next, we have I think that's Thomas
Thomas Massie. Yes, I'm going to I'm
going to say Thomas Massie is my S.
I know Thomas Massie.
Um
we're very friendly with each other.
We have a great friend in common, and so
we all go to baseball games together. I
was very disappointed that he lost his
congressional race, but he's going on to
bigger things.
Um Thomas Massie is most definitely
the kind of person
that people want to be close to.
He attracts that kind of attention,
positive attention. I think he'd be a
successful case officer.
Next, we have Matt Gaetz.
You might remember Matt Gaetz is a
former congressman from Florida.
Um he was briefly named as Attorney
General of the United States, but then
dropped out when Republican senators uh
said that they they wouldn't support
him.
But Matt Gaetz is another one of those
people that that people like to be
around. He's very personable. I've come
to know him quite well.
And I'm going to put him
uh next to Ro Khanna as an A. I think he
would be
he would be a good case officer.
Listen.
Next, we have Max Miller.
Max Miller, of course, is a Republican
Congressman from
Ohio.
Max Miller has been credibly accused of
beating his wife,
scalding her with hot water,
and breaking the collarbone of their
2-year-old daughter.
That is not the kind of person you want
at the CIA. There's an internal rule at
the CIA that if you have been credibly
accused of
spousal abuse or domestic abuse, you may
not carry a gun.
And if you're overseas and you're not
allowed to carry a gun, you're no good
to the CIA.
He gets an F. I don't even know if we
have F on our chart. He's an F.
Most definitely.
Next, we have Mike Johnson. Mike Johnson
is the Speaker of the House.
People who know Mike Johnson say he's a
lovely person as a human being. He's a
terrible politician and arguably the
weakest Speaker of the House in American
history.
The criticisms of Mike Johnson come
mostly from Republican members of the
House.
And they say that his biggest negative
is that he promises everything to
everybody and then delivers on nothing.
I'm going to I'm going to put him
at a D.
He might be able to push some paper,
but he would be a terrible case officer.
Next, we have Jim Jordan.
Jim Jordan is a powerful Congressman
from the state of Ohio.
He's the chairman of the I think it's
the Judiciary Committee or the
Homeland Security Committee in the
House. Something like one of the very
big committees.
Um
I sort of have a love-hate thing going
with Jim Jordan.
He talks a tough game.
But um
but he doesn't really get a whole lot of
things done. And one of the big problems
that I have with Jim Jordan is before he
was in Congress, he was the wrestling
coach at Ohio State University.
And
wrestlers repeatedly went to him and
said, "Coach, we're being sexually
abused by the team doctor."
And he did nothing to help them.
Nothing.
And so I think that as a case officer,
he probably couldn't be trusted to live
within the confines of the rules. I'm
going to put him D.
Ay, ay, ay. Next we've got Gavin Newsom.
Listen, as a human being, I loathe Gavin
Newsom.
I actually
crossed paths with him recently at the
uh White House Correspondents uh
dinner.
The the party.
>> [gasps]
>> And um
I elected to not shake his hand.
One of the reasons why I so loathe Gavin
Newsom
is that when he was the mayor of San
Francisco and he was running for
Lieutenant Governor of California,
his best friend
was
running his campaign.
And there was an incident where Newsom
was supposed to appear at a debate and
he said, "I just can't do it. I'm
swamped, too much going on. Can you
represent me at the debate?" His best
friend said, "Of course." He goes to
represent Newsom at the debate. Newsom
wasn't busy.
Newsom was sleeping with his best
friend's wife.
And they got caught.
And Newsom
apologized to the people of California.
Not to his best friend for banging his
wife
and just upending a lifelong friendship.
The wife resigned. She She was working
for Newsom, too.
They got divorced.
But, I don't know. The guy just has
scumbag written all over him. I'm going
to give him a D.
>> [gasps]
>> Marjorie Taylor Greene
>> [sighs]
I disagree with Marjorie Taylor Greene
on 99% of the issues. I think she's not
a serious person.
I think that she has
pulled down the level of debate
on Capitol Hill when she was on Capitol
Hill. She's resigned effective uh
January of this year.
But, the thing that bothers me the most
about Marjorie Taylor Greene is I think
she's just not very bright. I hate to
say that.
I think she's not very bright. And
because of that, I don't think she could
follow all the issues that a case
officer needs to follow.
And I'm going to put her in the D.
Next, we have Jon Ossoff.
Jon Ossoff is one of the senators from
Georgia.
Until about 6 months ago, I didn't
really know a lot about Jon Ossoff.
I've come to know a lot about Jon
Ossoff, and I really like this guy.
First of all, as an aside, his
grandfather,
on his mother's side, was Australian.
And he was one of those
heroes
who parachuted onto the island of Crete
in the middle of the night to drive the
Nazis out of Crete and thus out of
Greece, one of the heroes of the
liberation of Greece during World War
II.
I've also come to know Jon Ossoff as
one of these rare people on Capitol Hill
who is as honest as the day is long.
You don't have to like all of his
politics or his policies,
but this guy belongs with Thomas Massie
as an S.
Honest.
Exactly the kind of person you would
want as a CIA CIA case officer.
Marco Rubio.
This is probably the toughest one.
And it's tough because Marco Rubio is
really really smart.
But he's really really wrong on so many
of these issues.
If Marco Rubio were in the CIA when I
was in the CIA, he would be one of these
guys jumping up and down to invade Iraq,
invade Iraq, invade Iraq.
Well, we said at the time that that was
nuts.
But the decision has been made and we
invaded Iraq anyway.
I fear that he would be one of those
guys that would focus more on policy
than on intelligence. I'm going to give
him a C.
And I'm giving him a C that high of a
grade only because he's so bright.
But I think he would be far better,
you know, in politics, let's say,
than in intelligence.
I don't know, should I put him lower
than AOC? Maybe I should
Maybe I should bump AOC up to a up to a
B.
I'm going to bump AOC up to a B cuz I
think I think she's better than Rubio
and Rubio deserves a C.
Nancy Pelosi. Ay, ay, ay, ay, ay.
I think Nancy Pelosi
is one of the more dangerous figures in
modern politics.
I don't like her.
I don't trust her.
I think she is emblematic of exactly
what's wrong with our political system
right now.
I'm not even going to talk about her.
I'm just going to give her a D. Katie
Porter is not even worthy of discussion.
We're putting her in a D. I I will
discuss her for a minute. Katie Porter
was a congressman a congresswoman from
California.
I I never saw anybody that
that was so publicly, obviously,
blatantly
trying to be president
than Katie Porter. Yeah, she was in
Congress, but she wanted to be a
senator. No, she wants to be a governor.
No, she wants to be the mayor of Los
Angeles. No, she wants to be president
of the United States. It's like, "Lady,
pick a job and stick with it." But, the
reason why I put her as a D is that she
had a reputation as being one of the
meanest members
of Congress.
She ended up having to drop out of the
race for governor of California because
she was so cruel
to her staff. She would swear at them,
berate them, throw things at them, call
them names, humiliate them. And this
kept leaking out, and this wasn't just,
you know, Joe Blow calling the
Washington Post. This was a parade of
current and former staff members sit
saying that she was
she was Satan.
And so, I think politically she's done.
Oh, George Santos. Look,
George Santos
should never have been in Congress in
the first place. George Santos is
Oh, God, he's a convicted felon. He's a
a
well-known liar. Uh
you know, not just a liar. He's what
psychiatrists call a fabulist.
Where he'll just make up a story
and not only a story, he'll make up like
deep details of a story and present
these intimate, intricate details as,
you know,
as a major part of his life and
literally none of it ever happened. None
of it.
And then when called on the carpet, he
just doubles down with another story.
And none of this stuff ever happened.
He's got to be an F. We don't have the F
there, so we got to put him as a D.
I have come to know Tucker Carlson very,
very well.
I consider Tucker to be a friend. Tucker
has said
about me, just like I say about Tucker,
that we disagree on a whole lot of
issues.
Tucker's very conservative.
I'm not.
I mean, I guess I am on some things, but
um
but Tucker is one of the most honest and
decent people
I've ever known.
Like I say, you can disagree with his
politics,
but he is one of the most honest and
decent people I've ever known.
Um
a CIA case officer? I don't know. CIA
director? Is an S.
I would put him right up there at the
very top.
I think Tucker Carlson would be a
fantastic CIA director.
Yeah, give him an S.
And next we have Vice President J.D.
Vance.
I actually have a lot of respect for
J.D. Vance because of where he came
from. I understand his path to
conservatism. I disagree with it in a
lot of ways, but I get it. I read his
book, um
uh Hillbilly Elegy. I didn't see the
movie, but the book was captivating.
Uh he's from southwestern Ohio,
Appalachia, grew up poor, his mom was a
was a drug addict. He was raised by his
grandmother
for whom he had deep love and respect.
Um
you know, I think I'm going to put him
as an A because I think that
just judging by the quality of his
character
I believe that he could be trusted as a
CIA case officer.
Yeah.
And last we have Senator Mark Warner,
the vice chairman of the Senate
Intelligence Committee,
former governor of Virginia.
Uh Mark Warner
I'm told
does not like me
at all
and doesn't think I should be pardoned.
I'm going to put that aside. I've never
met the man.
We've never exchanged a harsh word.
But
I'm told he doesn't like me, and that's
fine.
With that said, he's very very smart.
He's a terrific manager.
He's an accomplished leader, not just in
government, but in private industry.
And I think I'm going to have to put him
up there
at the top.
I'm going to say S. I think he would
actually be quite an excellent CIA
director.
And uh
and he's honest.
And we know that because he's he's been
in public life for decades
and he's honest.
So, anyway,
I think that's a pretty fair
representation of where I stand on these
people.
Yeah. Good. And we're going to do more
of this. I think that's kind of fun.
Couple of other little things that I
wanted to mention, uh folks.
Um there's a clip of me that's gone
viral that I think deserves a little bit
of explanation.
Um JB, if we could, let's cut to that
clip real quick.
>> You know, we're [music] going to we're
going to send you someplace that you're
not going to like.
>> And he's like, "I'm not afraid [music]
of Guantanamo." I said, "Guantanamo?"
I never said I was going to send you to
Guantanamo.
>> I'm going to send you to Jerusalem.
>> Okay, well, listen.
>> [sighs]
>> When I was the chief of counterterrorism
operations in Pakistan in 2002,
um
I caught a guy who was
particularly dangerous.
This is not your run-of-the-mill
Al-Qaeda fighter,
you know, making jihad against the
Americans. This guy was
near the top.
Particularly dangerous.
And
in my interrogation of him,
and remember, I was always a hands-off
guy. I treated people with respect
because it was my experience that if you
engage them in a conversation and you
treat them with respect, nine times out
of 10, they're going to cooperate.
This guy was a true believer.
And he had obviously read and absorbed
the Al-Qaeda training manual. He tried
everything that the training manual told
him to do. He pretended to faint, and he
would fall off the chair, and then he
would open one eye to see if I was
looking at him, and I'd say, "Get the
back on the chair."
He pretended to have severe abdominal
pain. I'm like, "Look, I read the
training manual. I know you're faking
it." And then he we stop.
But he just would not cooperate and and
he was harsh about it. He was like, I
you, I your mother, I
your sister, I your president. It's
like, all right, all right.
And I said, listen,
I'm the nicest guy you're going to meet
here.
My colleagues are not nice. So we could
do this the easy way or we can do it the
hard way. Totally up to you.
And I said, and if you don't cooperate
with me now,
we're going to send you somewhere
terrible.
And he said, I'm not afraid of
Guantanamo.
I said, I'm not going to send you to
I'm going to send you to Jerusalem.
Now, we don't send people to Jerusalem.
We never did.
I said it to scare him.
And it scared him.
And he talked.
So nothing ever happened to him. We
ended up sending him back to his own
country to face the justice system
there.
Which
probably made him wish he had been in
Guantanamo.
But uh
no, we don't send people to Jerusalem. I
just felt like that clip deserved a
little bit of context.
And I want to say one last thing.
Many of you have asked me about my
watch,
which is very funny to me.
I love this watch. I bought this watch
26 and a half years ago.
And it actually has a little bit of
story. This is an Omega Seamaster 120.
It's a nice watch. Let's see if you can
Yeah, there it is. Omega Seamaster 120.
It was Christmas 1999.
I was married to my first wife and our
marriage was not going well at all.
And so
there is no such thing as marriage
counseling in Greece. We We tried the It
just didn't exist. We tried going to
this priest and he was just like he
yelling at her, "Just do what he says.
He's the husband." And that just wasn't
going to get us anywhere.
So, it was Christmas and I decided to go
hog wild and I bought her this gorgeous
heavy $2,000
gold necklace. I bought her this
six-book set that she really wanted. I
bought her a beautiful dress to wear at
parties.
And she bought me a white button-down
shirt.
That was it.
And I was offended and disappointed.
Well,
the day after Christmas, December 26th,
1999, I had to fly to a European country
to recruit an asset.
I had been developing this guy. It was
just
the situation was very sensitive. We
decided to fly to another country and
that way we could sit in public and have
a good conversation and
formalize our relationship. So, I'm in
the Athens airport in the duty-free and
I saw this watch.
And I thought to myself, "I need a
watch." I was wearing, you know, a $35
Timex Indiglo watch, if you remember
those from the '90s.
And um I thought, "You know what?
I'm the only one working. It's my money.
Merry Christmas to me."
And I bought myself this watch.
And I love it. And I've been wearing it
ever since. It's been 26 and a half
years.
Omega makes a fantastic watch and it's
considered a luxury brand, but it's not
like a lose your mind luxury brand like,
you know, Patek Philippe or
Baume & Mercier or something like that.
Love my Omega. Thanks for asking. Folks,
we really, really appreciate you
watching uh the the show. Thank you for
subscribing. Thank you for your
questions. Please keep them coming.
We're going to do lots more and we wish
you all the best. I'm John Kiriakou and
this is Briefing Room.